USMAN TAHIR



itsusmantahir1999@gmail.com



03095016490



linkedin.com/in/usman-tahir-a80b5121a



https://usmantahir.netlify.app/

Summary

Experienced Software Quality Assurance with over 1 years of experience a demonstrated history of working in the Software Industry in different technologies (like web2.0,web3.0,wordpress,android,ios and game) in different types of software(like e-commerce website and application, Wallpaper and Themes apps, Rental Guarantee website) as Automation and Manual Testing.

Experience



Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Cherry Byte Technologies

Jun 2022 - Present (8 months)

Manual Testing of Multiple websites, web applications, game and mobile applications

Database Testing(MANUAL) of Multiple websites, web applications and mobile applications through MYSQL Workbench

API Testing of Multiple websites, web applications and mobile applications through POSTMAN

Automation Testing of Multiple websites, web applications through JEST and CYPRESS

Create detailed, comprehensive and well structured test cases

Estimate, prioritize, plan and coordinate testing activities.

Review and analyze user stories to determine reason-ability, test-ability, resource requirements

Bug reporting and verification of bugs reported

Proactively engage and communicate with development team and QA manager regarding issues and their fixes

Documenting all the issues and their fixes

DSR (Daily Status Report) of projects

Scrum Meeting on Daily Basis



Software Quality Assurance Engineer Intern

Black Box Labz

Mar 2022 - May 2022 (3 months)

Manual Testing of Multiple websites, web applications, game and mobile applications

Create detailed, comprehensive and well structured test cases

Estimate, prioritize, plan and coordinate testing activities.

Review and analyze user stories to determine reason-ability, test-ability, resource requirements

Bug reporting and verification of bugs reported

Proactively engage and communicate with development team and QA manager regarding issues and their fixes

Documenting all the issues and their fixes

DSR (Daily Status Report) of projects

Education



Lahore Garrison University

Bachelor's of Software Engineering(BSSE), Computer Software Engineering Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

Government Khawaja Rafique Shaheed College (GKRSC)

Intermediate, F.Sc Pre Eng 2015 - 2017

OTI Grammer High School

Matric, Science 2013 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

JAVASCRIPT - Sololearn 1024-14624181

Software Testing - Great Learning DVPUJQHZ

- **SQL** Sololearn 1060-14624181
- Microsoft Excel Great Learning VGGXKXJR

Skills

Manual Testing • Jira • Agile Methodologies • Scrum • SQL • Database Testing • API Testing • Postman API • JavaScript • Cypress.io